Easy.
Saw some turkeys on the way here.
Crossed right in front of me
like I wasn't even there.
How rude of them.
That's what happens when you spend
six days a week working in the mines.
Stupid birds start to think
they own these woods.
When's the tour leave?
Couple hours.
Well, let's go.
Hey!
- Hey. You're okay.
- Let go!
You're okay. You're safe.
It's okay. You're here with me.
You're with me.
Okay, okay.
I'm sorry.
We should...
We should go.
Are you coming to the train station?
I think you have enough people
saying goodbye without me there.
Only a few I actually care about.
It might be easier if I didn't.
It's only a few weeks.
I'll be back before the snow melts.
A lot can happen in a few weeks.
Are we gonna do this again?
Gale, it was an act.
Yeah, it was a good one.
I did what I had to do to survive.
If I didn't, I'd be dead.
I had to do that.
At least once.
Haymitch!
Haymitch, wake up. It's Tour Day.
Haymitch.
What are you doing?
Cameras are gonna be here in an hour.
If you wanted to be babied,
you should've asked Peeta.
Asked me what?
Asked you to wake me
without giving me pneumonia.
You are a strangely dislikeable person.
But you do have your virtues.
Would you like some bread, Katniss?
No, I ate at the Hob, but thank you.
You're welcome.
You two have a lot of warming up to do
before show time.
Which is in an hour,
so take a bath, Haymitch.
I just did.
Did you have a good walk, dear?
- Walk? I was just out...
- We have visitors.
Miss Everdeen. This way, please.
Such bravery.
Such spirit.
Such...
Contempt.
President Snow.
What an honor.
My dear, I think we can make this
so much simpler
if we agree not to lie to each other.
What do you think?
Yes, I think that would save time.
Sit down, please.
I have a problem, Miss Everdeen.
A problem that began the moment you
revealed those poison berries in the arena.
If that Head Gamemaker, Seneca Crane,
had had any brains at all,
he would have blown you to bits
then and there.
But here you are.
I expect you can guess where he is.
Yes, I think so.
After that fiasco,
there was nothing left to do
but to let you play
out your little scenario.
And you were very good.
That whole love-crazed,
besotted schoolgirl routine.
Impressive. Truly.
You convinced the people in The Capitol.
Unfortunately, not everyone
in the districts fell for it.
I mean, you can't know this,
but in several of them,
people viewed your little trick
with the berries as an act of defiance.
Not as an act of love.
And if a girl from District 12 of all places
can defy The Capitol and walk away unharmed,
what is to prevent them
from doing the same?
What is to prevent, say, an uprising?
That can lead to revolution.
And then, in a fraction of time,
the whole system collapses.
It must be a fragile system, if it can be
brought down by just a few berries.
Yes, it is, indeed.
But not in the way you imagine it.
How should I imagine?
You should imagine thousands
upon thousands of your people dead.
This town of yours reduced to ashes.
Imagine it gone.
Made radioactive.
Buried under dirt as if it had
never existed, like District 13.
You fought very hard in The Games,
Miss Everdeen.
But they were games.
Would you like to be in a real war?
No.
Good. Neither would I.
Did your mother make these?
Peeta.
He's a lovely boy.
Tell me.
At what point did he realize
the depth of your indifference towards him?
I'm not indifferent.
Don't lie!
You promised.
Why don't you just kill me now?
I don't want to kill you.
I want us to be friends.
But if not friends, then allies.
What do I need to do?
When you and Peeta are on tour,
you need to smile. You need to be grateful.
But, above all, you need to be madly,
prepared-to-end-it-all in love.
- You think you can manage that?
- Yes.
Yes, what?
- I'll convince them.
- No.
Convince me.
For you, Miss Everdeen.
Do convince me.
For the sake of your loved ones.
Stop.
Take it all in.
This is sacred ground.
History was made here.
You'll get used to the smell.
Hello!
There she is. My greatest triumph!
Our little superstar.
Sweetie, we've missed you.
What a cute little house.
So quaint, isn't it?
Of course, you've heard about Cinna?
What happened to Cinna?
Oh, dear, he's a fashion star.
You're his muse.
Everyone in The Capitol's wearing him.
Everyone.
- Everyone.
- Well, not everyone.
Cinna!
Katniss?
Katniss, is this your sister?
Oh, sweetie!
Are you okay?
Just adorable!
- Yeah.
- Ready to work?
- All right. Good.
Welcome!
Last year, the 74th Hunger Games brought
us the greatest love story of our time.
Two brave young people, against all odds,
chose to die rather than to lose each other.
As a nation, we shared their agony.
But we had so little
time to revel in their joy.
It's time!
She's done, she's lovely.
We must feed the monster.
All right now.
Let's go to District 12
and find our star-crossed lovers!
You're excited. You're in love.
Big smiles for the
camera in three, two, one.
There she is! Katniss Everdeen!
The Girl on Fire.
And there he is!
Peeta Mellark! The Baker's Boy.
Trouble in paradise.
I hope they're all right.
Anyone at home?
Should we come back later?
Sorry, Caesar.
Please. It's all right. It's your day.
It's your day. So how's it going?
We're good.
That's it? That's all we get? "We're good"?
So taciturn all of a sudden.
Peeta, give me some details!
Yeah, things are great here in 12.
Thanks to the generosity of The Capitol,
we've never been closer.
Twenty-five yards, to be exact.
Fantastic!
We'll be checking in with both of you
throughout the Victory Tour.
Thank you so much,
Katniss Everdeen and Peeta Mellark!
Wonderful!
Everybody in motion.
We are out of here in 10.
- That was nice acting.
- You, too.
Almost thought that kiss was real.
Come along, children, we are on a schedule.
The train awaits!
Fabulous food, fabulous wine,
the massages, spa treatments.
I told them
nothing but the best for my two Victors.
It all needs to be...
Fabulous?
Exactly.
Now, the schedule is a bit of a bear.
12 days, 12 districts.
But it's mostly parties, celebrations,
adoring fans to greet you
at every stop along the way,
and then we wrap it up in The Capitol.
All you need to do is give a few speeches,
wave to the crowds,
and enjoy your time in the spotlight.
You've earned it.
What did you say?
Katniss.
I said, "Enjoy it,
Katniss, you've earned it."
By killing people.
Young lady...
I'm really not in the mood for a lecture.
I'll apologize to Effie later.
I thought you were Haymitch.
You don't have to apologize to anybody.
Including me.
I know it's not fair of me to hold you
to things you said in The Games.
You saved us. I know that.
But I can't go on acting for the cameras, and
then just ignoring each other in real life.
So if you can stop looking at me like I'm
wounded, then I can quit acting like it.
And then maybe
we have a shot at being friends.
I've never been very good at friends.
For starters, it does help
when you know the person.
I hardly know anything about you except
that you're stubborn and good with a bow.
That about sums me up.
No, there's more than that,
you just don't want to tell me.
It's like I said, I'm...
See, Katniss, the way
the whole friend thing works
is you have to tell each
other the deep stuff.
- The deep stuff?
- Yeah.
Like what?
Like...
What's your favorite color?
Well, now you've stepped over the line.
Seriously, though, what is it?
Green.
What's yours?
Orange.
- Like Effie's hair?
- No. Not that orange.
More like a sunset kind of orange.
Did you see that?
What?
Well, I never.
This is not very festive.
The mayor will make
some introductory remarks.
And then you just have to say a few words.
It's customary, of course, to give a brief
eulogy to the district's fallen Tributes.
For 11, that's Thresh and Rue.
Here are the speeches.
I can do the talking if you want.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Victors of the 74th Hunger Games.
Katniss Everdeen and Peeta Mellark!
Smile, smile, smile, smile.
Stand up straight. You're on camera.
Thank you.
We're honored to be here with you today.
And to be with the families
of your fallen Tributes.
He put down the cards.
- Though they fought and lived with honor...
- Why do I bother?
And dignity until the end,
both Thresh and Rue
were so young.
But our lives aren't
just measured in years.
They're measured in
the lives of people we touch around us.
For myself,
for Katniss,
we know that without Rue and without
Thresh, we wouldn't be standing here today.
So in recognition of that, knowing that
it in no way can make up for your loss,
we'd like to donate one month of our
winnings to the families of the Tributes,
every year, for the rest of our lives.
Shit.
Can he do that?
He can't. But he did.
Why doesn't he just stick to the cards?
Thank you.
I just wanted to say that
I didn't know Thresh.
I only spoke to him once.
He could have killed me,
but instead he showed me mercy.
That's a debt I'll never be able to repay.
I did know Rue.
She wasn't just my ally, she was my friend.
I see her in the flowers
that grow in the meadow by my house.
I hear her in a Mockingjay song.
I see her in my sister Prim.
She was too young,
too gentle.
And I couldn't save her.
I'm sorry.
No! No!
Wait! Wait!
No! Leave him alone! Leave him alone!
No! Let me go! Please leave him alone!
No!
You! No, no, no!
Come here! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop!
What did I do?
Come on.
Shut up.
In all my years, I've never seen...
You two have a very simple task.
I never meant for anyone to get killed.
He has to know that.
What are you talking about?
Who has to know what?
Snow. He came to see me.
He's worried about
rebellion in the districts.
He thinks that
they don't believe our love story.
So he wants you to make them believe it?
- To calm things down.
- You know, Katniss,
you shoulda told me that
before I went out there,
and tried to give these people the money.
I'm sorry. I didn't know what to do.
He threatened to kill my family.
Well, I have family, too.
Okay? People that I need to protect.
What about them? Who protects them?
Katniss, what were you thinking?
I was thinking about Rue.
Haymitch, please...
Please, just help me get through this trip.
Please, just help us get through this.
This trip? Girl, wake up.
This trip doesn't end
when you get back home.
You never get off this train.
You two are mentors now.
That means that every year,
they're gonna drag you out,
and broadcast the details of your romance.
Every year, your private
life becomes theirs.
From now on, your
job is to be a distraction.
So people forget what
the real problems are.
- So what do we do?
- You're gonna smile.
You're gonna read the cards
that Effie gives you.
And you're gonna live happily ever after.
Think you can do that?
Yeah?
Come here.
You're gonna be okay. I promise.
Katniss and I
want to share with you our victory.
And our gratitude to The Capitol
for bringing us together.
It was the bond of love,
forged in the crucible of The Games
that was our greatest prize.
For it is love and true love
that allows us all to bear our hardships.
That mends the heart and banishes
loneliness and gives meaning to our lives.
We also want to share with you
the sorrows of your losses.
The Tributes of this...
The Tributes of this district
were brave and noble warriors.
They brought honor to their families
and pride to their people.
We are all of us united, both victors and
vanquished, in serving a common purpose.
Thank you.
One day, I'm gonna volunteer.
Just like you did.
It was just a dream. I'm sorry.
It's okay. I get 'em, too.
Goodnight.
Peeta.
Will you stay with me?
Yeah.
Always.
We are all of us united,
both victors and vanquished,
in serving a common purpose.
- The power and glory of The Capitol.
- Put down the cards!
Tell us what you really think!
Panem today. Panem tomorrow.
Panem forever.
Your hair looks lovely, darling.
When did you start wearing it like that?
Everyone at school wears it like this now,
Grandpa.
Snow is watching us.
If he wants you to pacify the districts,
I promise you, he's not happy.
Instead of being in love, you two sound
like you're reciting from a drilling manual.
You try reading that stuff
that Effie writes us.
Tell that to President Snow
when you see him two days from now.
I'm open to suggestions.
We could get married.
That's not helping.
I'm serious.
If, like you said, we're on this train
forever, it's gonna happen eventually.
Why not now?
It does make a
statement. I'll give you that.
Yeah, sure. Let's do it.
Just when you thought things
couldn't get more exciting
going into a very special Quarter Quell,
our two lethal lovers,
my favorite expression,
from District 12
have surprised us
with a new twist in their love affair.
Let's take a look.
A fairy tale ending
for two star-crossed lovers.
That's beautiful. Beautiful.
And then tonight,
the tour that began in the hollows
of District 12 will end where?
The Presidential Palace.
The party of the year.
Eyes bright. Chins up. Smiles on.
I'm talking to you, Katniss.
Now, there'll be photographers. Interviews.
Everyone will be here to celebrate you.
My Victors.
Breathe it all in, children.
This is all for you.
It's cozy.
Attitude.
Come, come.
Come along.
Excuse us, excuse us.
Come, come.
Hold hands.
And the library. All mahogany.
Hello, hello!
Not yet, not yet. No, no, no.
Curtains!
Everybody who's anybody is here.
And they all want to meet you.
Flavius! Octavia!
Try one of these. They are divine.
No, I can't eat another thing.
- Here.
- What's this?
It's for when you're full.
It makes you sick.
So you can go on eating.
How else could you taste everything?
I think it's time for a dance.
Katniss?
People are starving in 12.
Here, they're just throwing it up
to stuff more in.
Katniss? Peeta.
This is Plutarch Heavensbee.
Head Gamemaker.
Successor to Seneca Crane.
That's a tough act to follow.
Peeta!
May I?
Please.
So how do you like the party?
It's a little overwhelming.
It's appalling.
Still, if you abandon your moral judgment,
it can be fun.
So are you having fun?
I'm the Head Gamemaker. Fun is my job.
Thought that was what happened
to Seneca Crane.
Too much fun.
Seneca decided to quit breathing.
Decided.
It was that or poison berries.
Being Head Gamemaker has never been
the most secure job in the world.
Then why are you here?
Same reason as you. I volunteered.
Why?
Ambition.
The chance to
make The Games mean something.
The Games don't mean anything.
They only mean to scare us.
Well, maybe it was you
who inspired me to come back.
The Presidential welcome.
I'm sure we'll meet again.
Katniss, come. The President awaits.
You think we convinced him?
I'm not sure what else we can do.
Tonight, on this, the
last day of their tour,
I want to welcome our two Victors.
Two young people who embody our ideals
of strength and valor.
And I, personally, want
to congratulate them
on the announcement of their engagement.
Your love has inspired us.
And I know it will go on inspiring us
every day
for as long as you may live.
Look at them.
She's not who they think she is.
She's not a leader.
She just wants to save her own skin.
It's as simple as that.
I think that's true.
But she's become
a beacon of hope for the rebellion.
And she has to be eliminated.
I agree she should
die. But in the right way.
At the right time.
It's moves and countermoves.
That's all we gotta look at.
Katniss Everdeen is a symbol.
Their Mockingjay.
They think she's one of them.
We need to show that she's one of us.
We don't need to destroy her.
Just the image.
Then we let the people do the rest.
What do you propose?
Shut down the black markets.
Take away what little they have.
Then double
the amount of floggings and executions.
Put them on TV. Broadcast them live.
Sow fear. More fear.
It won't work. Fear does not work
as long as they have hope.
And Katniss Everdeen is giving them hope.
She's engaged.
Make everything about that.
What kind of dress is she gonna wear?
Floggings.
What's the cake gonna look like?
Executions.
Who's gonna be there? Fear.
Blanket coverage. Shove it in their faces.
Show them that she is one of us now.
They're gonna hate her so much,
they might just kill her for you.
Brilliant.
When did you...
We need to talk.
Where are we gonna run away?
Into the woods.
Like we always talked about.
If we leave right now, we can be
far away from here by tonight.
Yeah, who's "we"?
You, me and your fiancé?
It's not just me and Peeta anymore.
Snow threatened to have you killed.
Anyone else?
Well, he didn't exactly
give me a copy of the list
but a good guess,
it includes both of our families.
Unless what? You and Peeta get married?
Unless nothing now.
Gale, we can do it.
You said yourself that we could do it
the morning of the Reaping.
What do you say now?
Do you love me?
Gale, you know how I feel about you.
But I can't think about anyone
that way right now.
The only thing that I can think about
every day, every waking moment
since the Reaping, is how afraid I am.
There's no room for anything else.
But maybe, if we got away from here,
if we went somewhere safe,
it could be different.
I could be different.
You think maybe the President's bluffing?
He's not bluffing.
Not with what's going on in the districts.
What do you mean?
What did you see?
There were people fighting
in the streets, and fires,
and Peacekeepers were gunning them down,
but the people were...
What? The people were what?
They were fighting back.
It's happening.
It's finally happening.
I should've just eaten the berries in
the arena and died like I was supposed to.
Then everything would be back to normal
and everyone would be safe.
Safe for what?
To starve? Work like slaves?
Send their kids to the Reaping?
You haven't hurt people, Katniss.
You've given them an opportunity.
They just have to be
brave enough to take it.
There's already talk in the mines.
People wanna fight.
We have to go, Gale, before they kill us.
They will kill us.
What about the other families?
The ones who stay. What happens to them?
- People are looking to you, Katniss.
- I don't want anyone looking to me.
I can't help them.
You do what you want.
I'm staying here.
Commander Thread, welcome to District 12.
Let's get to work.
- Let's go! Keep moving!
- Stay close!
Find and clear.
Burn all contraband.
Let me go!
Ripper!
My eye!
I'm gonna get you out of here.
No!
Leave her be! Stop!
In the square.
Here.
Yeah, hold that on there.
No!
No! No! Stop!
Katniss!
It's okay.
Just go. It's okay.
Move.
You want another?
Go ahead.
- Get out of my way!
- No, you don't want to shoot her.
How about I shoot both of you?
Look, Commander, you're new here.
Trust me, I'm trying to help you.
I'm Haymitch.
You recognize her? Katniss Everdeen.
Darling of The Capitol.
She interfered with a Peacekeeper.
I never said she was smart.
Look, you already got
a couple of lashes in, right?
That's not good enough. She's an agitator.
- Easy, easy.
- Look...
You're sure Snow
wants three dead Victors here?
Because that's what we're looking at.
It's bad enough that you marked up her face
on the eve of the big wedding.
Let it go. And we will, too.
All right.
Okay.
But next time, it's the firing squad.
Excellent idea.
I don't care who she is.
Clear the square!
You're all under curfew.
Anyone out after dark
will be shot on sight.
Get 'em outta here.
It's Gale.
Get him here.
Here we go.
Really easy. Up, up.
Okay.
Okay. Thanks.
New Head Peacekeeper.
Not entirely peaceful.
Missed your eye. Doesn't need stitches.
- Make a snow coat.
- Peeta, get the snow. I'll grind the herbs.
What is that? That's hurting him.
He needs morphling.
It's okay.
Mom. No. I'll do it.
Oh, God.
Hold him, please.
That's better.
- Hey, Catnip.
- Hey.
Thought you'd be gone by now.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm gonna stay right here.
Cause all kinds of trouble.
Me, too.
Hey.
You wanna get some rest?
I can look after him for a while.
I'm gonna go get him more snow.
Hey.
How's your eye?
It's not my eye that's bothering me.
How can we live like this?
How can anybody live like this?
It's not living, but...
Since the last Games,
something is different.
I can see it.
What can you see?
Hope.
You understand that whatever I do
comes back to you and Mom.
I don't want you to get hurt.
You don't have to protect me. Or Mom.
We're with you.
I love you.
I love you, too.
The broadcast cut out here.
Before any of the excitement happened.
- How many people saw it?
- Hard to say.
There was a five second delay,
but it happened fast.
If you cannot contain Katniss Everdeen,
then I will have to terminate her.
I understand that.
And not just her.
Her entire species has to be eliminated.
Her species, sir?
The other Victors.
Now, because of her,
they all pose a threat.
Because of her,
they all think they're invincible.
Whatever game you think you're playing,
those out there are not playing it with you.
There's a way we can still win.
It's what we Gamemakers
like to call "a wrinkle."
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the 75th year of The Hunger Games.
And it was written
in the charter of The Games
that every 25 years,
there would be a Quarter Quell
to keep fresh for each new generation
the memory of those who died
in the uprising against The Capitol.
Each Quarter Quell is distinguished
by Games of a special significance.
And now on this the
75th anniversary of
our defeat of the rebellion,
we celebrate the 3rd Quarter Quell
as a reminder that even the strongest
cannot overcome the power of The Capitol.
On this, the 3rd Quarter Quell Games,
the male and female Tributes
are to be reaped from the existing pool
of Victors in each district.
No!
Who does he mean?
Victors shall present themselves
on Reaping Day
- regardless of age...
- Katniss...
state of health
or situation.
No.
Peeta.
There she is.
Finally did the math?
And you've come to, what?
Ask me to... Die?
I'm here to drink.
Finally, something I can help you with.
What's it say that Peeta was here
45 minutes ago begging to save your life
and you only just now show up?
It means we have to save him.
You could live 100 lifetimes
and never deserve that boy.
Come on, Haymitch.
Nobody decent ever wins The Games.
Nobody ever wins The Games. Period.
There are survivors.
There's no winners.
Peeta has to survive.
We have to do whatever
it takes to save him.
All right, if...
If they call his name,
I'll volunteer in his place.
Haymitch, thank you.
But they call my name and Peeta volunteers,
there's nothing I can do.
You can help him in the arena.
Like you did for me.
I think these Games are gonna be different.
I don't care. Do whatever you can.
Peeta lives. Not me.
Promise me.
Okay.
We should've gone when you said.
Welcome.
As we celebrate the 75th anniversary
and 3rd Quarter Quell
of The Hunger Games.
As always, ladies first.
The female Tribute from District 12,
Katniss Everdeen.
Wonderful.
And now for the men.
The male Tribute from District 12.
Haymitch Abernathy.
- I volunteer as Tribute.
- I can't let you do that.
You can't stop me.
- Peeta.
- Let go.
Very well.
The Tributes from District 12.
Katniss Everdeen
and Peeta Mellark.
Well, all that remains is...
Oh, no. But, but, but...
Katniss!
- I get to say goodbye.
- Katniss!
- New plan. Straight to the train.
- No, I have to say goodbye.
Katniss!
No.
Goodbye!
All right.
Before we begin, I've had a thought.
You don't say?
Katniss has her gold Mockingjay pin.
I have my hair.
I'm going to get you two boys
something gold.
Why is that?
A token.
Show them we are a team.
And they can't just...
Thank you.
All right. Now...
Everything will be different,
because it's a Quarter Quell.
The Capitol has spared no expense.
A new training center.
New Tribute living quarters.
And of course, a very special arena.
But this year you'll be facing
other Victors. Capitol favorites.
Smart, cunning, skilled.
And they all know one another.
You two are the outsiders.
I want you guys to forget everything
you think you know about The Games.
Last year was child's play.
This year, you're dealing
with all experienced killers.
All right. What does that mean for us?
That means you're gonna have
to have some allies.
- Okay. I think that if...
- You're not the problem.
No.
Look, you're starting at a disadvantage.
Most of these people
have been friends for years.
That just puts us
higher on their kill list.
Do it your own way,
but I know these people.
You go it alone, their first move
is gonna be to hunt you down.
Both of you.
Katniss, come on.
How could any of us even trust each other?
It's not about trust.
It's about staying alive.
Cashmere and Gloss.
Brother and sister. District 1.
They won back-to-back Games.
Capitol favorites.
Lots of sponsors. They will be lethal.
And the other half of the Career Pack,
Brutus and Enobaria.
What's with her teeth?
She had them filed into fangs
so she could rip people's throats out.
She's committed. I'll give her that.
Wiress and Beetee.
Not fighters, but brilliant.
And weird. Real tech-savvy.
He won his Games by
electrocuting six Tributes at once.
The Morphlings. Masters of camouflage.
Basically, won their Games by
hiding until everyone else was dead.
Self-medicating ever
since. Which I applaud.
Not a threat.
Finnick Odair, right?
Yes. He won his Games at 14.
Youngest ever.
- Extremely humble.
- You're kidding.
Yes, I'm kidding.
He's a peacock. A total preener.
But he's The Capitol darling.
They love him here.
Charming, smart, and very skilled
at combat. Especially in water.
- What about weaknesses?
- One. Mags.
She volunteered for Annie.
Mags was his mentor
and basically raised him.
If he's trying to protect her in any way,
it exposes him.
A guy like that
has to know she's not gonna make it.
I bet when it really comes down to it,
he won't protect her.
Well, Katniss, I just hope when she goes,
she goes quickly.
She's actually a wonderful lady.
How'd we get here?
Katniss.
Hello, Finnick.
Do you want a sugar cube?
I mean, it's supposed to be
for the horses, but...
I mean, who cares about them, right?
They got years to eat sugar,
whereas you and I...
Well, if we see something sweet,
we better grab it.
No thanks. But I would love to
borrow that outfit someday.
You look pretty terrifying in that getup.
What happened to
the pretty little girl dresses?
I outgrew them.
You certainly did.
Shame about this Quell thing.
Now, you could've made out
like a bandit in The Capitol.
Jewels, money, anything you wanted.
Well, I don't like jewels
and I have more money than I need, so...
What did you do with all your wealth,
anyway?
I haven't dealt in anything
as common as money in years.
Then how do people pay for
the pleasure of your company?
With secrets.
What about you, Girl on Fire?
Any secrets worth my time?
I'm an open book.
Everybody always seems to know
my secrets before I know them myself.
Unfortunately, I think that's true.
I'm sorry you had to cancel your wedding.
I know how devastating
that must be for you.
Have a good day.
- Peeta.
- Finnick.
What'd he want?
To know all my secrets.
He'll have to get in line.
Tributes, mount up.
No waving and smiling, this time.
I want you to look straight ahead
as if the audience and this whole event
are beneath you.
That should be easy.
Press this when you're ready.
Good luck.
Here they come!
From District 12. Our favorites.
- Well...
- Or my favorite.
There it is!
Fire in the house!
Katniss! Katniss! Katniss!
Nice.
Way to make friends out there, you two.
Well, we learned from the best.
I wanna introduce you to
some special friends of mine.
This is Seeder. And
Chaff. From District 11.
He's very friendly.
Don't invite him over.
He'll drink up your liquor.
I'll see you guys soon.
Let's get some of that makeup off you
and talk about these other Tributes.
These Tributes are crazy.
No, not all of 'em. He's a good guy.
Carry on.
You guys look amazing.
Thank you.
My stylist is such an idiot.
District 7. Lumber. Trees.
I'd love to put my ax in her face.
So what do you think?
Now that the whole world
wants to sleep with you?
- I don't think that the whole world...
- I wasn't talking to you.
Okay.
Will you unzip?
Yeah.
Thanks. Let's do it again sometime.
Thank you.
Johanna Mason, District 7.
Remember, Katniss,
today's about making allies.
So far I'm not overwhelmed by our choices.
I guess we just try to figure out
who we trust least
and work our way backwards from there.
Friction generates heat.
Heat generates fire. In theory.
You should move your hands downward.
And faster, too.
- A little brute force...
- is always helpful.
Thank you.
By the corner of the table.
Plutarch?
No. Next to him.
Force field.
How do you know?
The shimmering.
Top left hand side.
Look.
There.
You see it?
Looks like glass.
To separate us and them.
Probably my fault.
I shot an arrow at them last year.
Electromagnetic.
How can you tell?
Is it obvious or something?
"Is it obvious?"
- They might as well have a sign.
- Look around you.
All the holograms, the lights,
every now and then they flicker. Why?
Because the force field
is taking up too much energy.
There's always a flaw in the system.
That's beautiful.
I saw you volunteer for that young girl.
It was really brave.
Prim is my sister.
If you...
If you teach me how to make a fishhook
like that, I could teach you how to hunt.
Yes, yes.
Do you wanna try with me?
Okay.
I'll go first.
Good news.
At least half the Tributes
want you as an ally.
Well, they saw her shoot.
Well, sweetheart,
you got your pick of the litter.
I want Wiress and Beetee.
Johanna calls them "Nuts" and "Volts."
- Well, okay, good. Now, who else?
- Mags.
All right, fine, then no one.
I'll tell them
you're still making up your mind.
District 3. Beetee Latier.
Report for individual assessment.
Peeta, how are we gonna kill these people?
District 12. Katniss Everdeen.
Report for individual assessment.
Miss Everdeen.
Miss Everdeen!
You have 10 minutes
to present your chosen skill.
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you for being here tonight
on the eve of the 75th Hunger Games!
We have never seen anything like this. And
we will never see anything like it again.
Because tonight, on this stage,
24 of Panem's brightest stars
will vie for the ultimate crown.
Tonight will be their final opportunity
to express their thoughts.
Our final opportunity to express our love.
And heartbreakingly,
to say goodbye to all but one.
What a night.
Let's hear it.
It's so exciting!
A wedding dress?
President Snow insisted,
but I made a few alterations.
You two made The Games a family affair.
You became everyone's brother and sister.
I don't know how we're going to let you go.
We're not going by choice.
You are our family.
And I don't see how anyone
can love us better.
So sweet. So sweet.
Are you all right, dear?
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
I just can't stop crying.
God! Does anybody actually believe this?
Apparently, everybody.
She is very good.
These Victors are angry, Katniss.
They'll say anything
to try and stop The Games.
I suggest you do the same.
Beetee...
You have contributed so much
to Panem over the years.
I don't know who we will miss more.
You or your brain.
If the Quarter Quell were written into law
by men, certainly, it can be unwritten.
Yes. Interesting concept.
Finnick...
I understand that you have a message
for somebody out there.
A special somebody.
Can we hear it?
My love,
you have my heart
for all eternity
and if I die in that arena,
my last thought will be of your lips.
We have seen a lot of tears here tonight.
But I see no tears in Johanna's eyes.
Johanna, you are angry.
Tell me why.
Well, yes, I'm angry.
You know,
I'm getting totally screwed over here.
The deal was that if I win the Hunger Games,
I get to live the rest of my life in peace.
But now you want to kill me again.
Well, you know what?...that!
And... everybody that had anything
to do with it!
All right then.
One woman's opinion.
Who's next?
All right, turn around.
I know it's a bad break
for everyone involved.
I think I'm done.
Will I be twirling tonight?
Save it for the end.
One minute. Is she ready?
Katniss.
You would have been
the most beautiful bride.
Thank you.
Let's go show them
what real beauty looks like.
It has to go more up.
Pretty, pretty, Katniss,
they're going to adore you.
And there are a lot of sponsors
in the audience,
so of course, just be your usual self.
Actually, be your happier self.
Really? A wedding dress?
Snow made me wear it.
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome...
- You know her...
- Make him pay for it.
As the Girl on Fire.
The Victor of last year's Hunger Games.
Katniss Everdeen!
Katniss Everdeen, you look fabulous.
Doesn't she?
My, my!
Now, Katniss,
this is
a very big and very emotional night
for all of us.
Wouldn't you say?
Don't go crying on me now, Caesar.
I can't make any promises. You know me.
You know I wouldn't believe you,
even if you did.
I love her! The Girl on Fire is so cheeky.
But, Katniss, on a more serious note.
I think we're all here a little disappointed,
more than a little disappointed,
that a certain wedding did not take place.
Aren't we, folks?
Alas. But am I correct in assuming
that this is the gown that you would
have worn on that day, yes or no?
Yes, President Snow thought
everyone would want to see it.
Well, President Snow, as usual, was right.
Was he not, folks?
I love it! I love it!
Don't you love it, folks?
It's incredible. It's so gorgeous.
Will you do us the honor?
Please? Please? Please?
Oh, my God!
Oh, my!
It's a bird.
It's got feathers. It's like a bird.
It's like a...
Like a Mockingjay.
Your stylist certainly has
outdone himself this time, hasn't he?
What theatricality!
Cinna!
Take a bow.
But, Peeta,
the wedding, the marriage, never to be?
Well, actually, we got married.
In secret.
A secret wedding?
All right. Do tell.
- We want our love to be eternal.
- Of course.
You know, Katniss and I,
we've been luckier than most.
And I wouldn't have any regrets at all
if it weren't...
If...
If it weren't for what? What?
If it weren't for the baby.
All right. This is news!
Let's find out more.
Calm down. This is news to all of us.
Call off The Games!
All right.
- Let's...
- Stop The Games!
Everybody, calm down.
It's a great night. A great night.
This is news to all of us.
All right, all right, all right.
We're going to find out
what we do about this.
Cancel The Games!
Stop The Games!
There's no way they'll cancel. They can't.
Baby bomb was a stroke of genius.
Unfortunately, Games are still on.
This is goodbye, for now.
Presents for the boys.
What is this?
Your token. Remember?
Hair for me. Pin for Katniss.
Gold bangle for you.
And for Peeta,
the medallion that we talked about.
Thank you, Effie.
We're a team. Aren't we?
And I'm so proud of my Victors.
So proud.
You're so...
Well, you both deserved so much better.
Thank you, Effie.
I am truly sorry.
Thank you, Haymitch.
For everything.
Any last advice?
Stay alive.
Haymitch, wait.
Remember our deal.
Do whatever it takes to keep him alive.
Promise me.
Okay.
Katniss, when you're in the arena,
remember who the real enemy is.
I don't want to be with
anyone else in there.
Just you.
If that's what you want.
That's what I want.
I'll see you soon.
Your tracker.
Look at this. They're holding hands.
I want them dead.
Be patient.
They're holding hands now, but the minute
the gun goes off, it'll be a bloodbath.
And the whole idea of revolution
will be discredited.
And the idea of her?
The idea of the Mockingjay?
The more allies she betrays,
the more friends she kills,
the more she reveals her true self.
As long as it ends with her picture
in the sky and the sound of cannon.
- And it shall.
- It better.
Let's watch her get her hands dirty first.
Excuse me.
Let's start.
This suit is light. No thermal.
So I'd guess tropics or desert.
Sixty seconds to launch.
That dress was beautiful.
I think it was the best
one you've ever made.
I thought you'd like it.
I just wanted to tell
you, because I don't...
Stop.
Remember, I'm still betting on you,
Girl on Fire.
Ten seconds to launch.
No!
Cinna! No!
No! No! No!
No! Cinna!
No! No!
No!
No, no...
Let the 75th Hunger Games begin.
May the odds be ever in your favor.
Peeta?
Ten, nine, eight,
seven, six,
five, four,
three, two,
one.
Good thing we're allies, right?
Where did you get that?
Where do you think?
Duck.
Don't trust 1 and 2.
I'll take this side. You hold them off.
I'll go find Peeta.
Katniss, Mags found him. He's over here.
Katniss, Katniss, go, go, go, go.
Okay, hold up. Hold up.
Here you go.
Okay. You all right now?
Okay?
God, it's hot.
We gotta find fresh water.
Well, I guess we're not
holding hands anymore.
You think that's funny?
Every time that cannon goes off,
it's music to my ears.
I don't care about any of them.
Good to hear.
Want to face the Career Pack alone?
What would Haymitch say?
Haymitch isn't here.
Let's keep moving.
Peeta, no!
Peeta?
He's not breathing. He's not breathing.
He's not breathing! Peeta!
Peeta?
Come on! Come on!
Please, wake up.
No.
- Come on.
- Come on!
Bring me in closer.
Cannon ready?
Come on. Come on. Come on, Peeta!
Please, Peeta. Peeta.
Come on.
Peeta? Peeta.
Oh, my God.
Be careful. There's a force field up there.
Oh, my God. You were dead.
You were dead. Your heart stopped.
It's okay.
It's working now.
- You... Do you wanna stand up?
- Yeah.
It's okay.
Someday I want to love someone that much.
And so you shall, my darling. So you shall.
Hang on.
The force field...
It's a dome. We're at
the edge of the arena.
We couldn't find any signs of fresh water.
It's gonna get dark soon.
We'll be safe with our backs protected.
We should set up camp. Take
turns sleeping. I can take first watch.
Not a chance.
Honey, that thing I did
back there for Peeta?
That was called "saving his life."
If I wanted to kill either of you,
I would've done it by now.
Why don't you get some rest?
I'll take the first watch.
Just for a little bit.
How's Peeta?
He's okay, I think.
Just dehydrated like the rest of us.
Eight.
Hey.
"Drink up"?
What is it?
It's from Haymitch.
I think it's a spile.
A what?
You're kidding me. You're kidding me.
Get some water.
I'm gonna get a leaf.
I'll get some for Mags.
There we go.
Want some more?
I counted 12.
Midnight?
Or the number of districts.
Well...
If you're not gonna sleep, I will.
Okay.
Run! Run! The fog is poison!
Come on, come on, come on.
There!
God! God!
Mags, please, please! Come on! Come on!
Peeta.
I can't carry him.
Peeta, please.
Peeta, please, stand up. We have to go.
Mags?
- Mags? Mags!
- Finnick.
- Mags!
Mags!
Finnick! Finnick, we have to go.
We have to get outta here.
We have to go.
All right, come on, come on. Come on.
Okay.
Shit!
The water! The water helps.
We need our weapons.
I'm sorry about Mags.
She was never gonna make it.
So...
What?
- Peeta.
- Yeah?
Walk over here slowly.
Get to the beach.
We gotta get to the beach!
- Who is that?
- A Morphling! Help me get her!
Hey, hey, hey. It's okay. It's okay.
Hey, you wanna see something?
Look up. Look.
Look at it. Look at that.
It's incredible, isn't it?
All those colors.
Don't worry about anything else.
I'll be right here with you.
It's okay. It's okay.
She sacrificed herself for me
and I didn't even know her name.
You think she sacrificed herself?
Looked like it.
That doesn't make any sense.
Look. For you.
Thank you.
That's new.
Someone's here.
Johanna?
- Johanna!
- Finnick!
Guess we have more allies.
Well...
I got 'em out.
We were all the way deep into the jungle
where I thought it was gonna be safe.
That's when the rain started.
I thought it was water.
It turned out to be blood.
- Tick tock.
- Hot, thick blood.
- It was coming down.
- Tick tock.
It was choking us.
We were stumbling around,
gagging on it, blind.
Tick tock.
- That's when Blight hit the force field.
- Tick tock.
Tick tock.
He wasn't much, but he was from home.
- Tick tock.
- What's wrong with her?
- She's in shock.
- Tick tock.
Dehydration isn't helping.
Do you have fresh water?
- We can get some.
- Just...
Tick tock.
Listen. Stop it!
- Hey! Lay off her!
- Just sit down!
Hey! What are you doing?
- Hey, hey, hey!
- I got them out for you!
It's okay. It's okay.
Let me go, Finnick!
- For me? What does that mean?
- Let me go.
- You did want them as allies.
- I'm fine.
Come on, let's get you cleaned up.
Tick tock.
- Tick tock.
- Tick tock!
Tick tock, okay.
What does Beetee have there?
The coil? It's some kind of wire.
Did he get it from the Cornucopia?
Took a knife in the back to get it.
- Tick tock! Tick tock!
- All right.
I can't.
Just... Have fun with "Nuts."
Tick tock.
It's a clock.
My God, it's a clock!
Wiress, you're a genius.
You're a genius!
This entire arena seems to be laid out
like a clock with a new threat every hour,
but they stay only within their wedge.
It all starts with the lightning.
Then the blood rain, fog, monkeys.
That's the first four hours.
At 10:00, that big wave
hits from over there.
Wiress, you're a genius.
Look, the tail points to 12.
That's where the lightning strikes
at noon and midnight.
- Strikes where?
- That big tree.
Good.
"Hickory dickory dock.
The mouse ran up the clock.
"The clock struck one, the mouse ran down.
"Hickory dickory dock."
So 12:00 to 1:00, lightning.
Then 1:00 to 2:00 is blood.
Then fog. And then monkeys.
"Hickory dickory dock.
The dog barked at the clock.
"The clock struck 3:00..."
And then 10:00 to 11:00, the wave.
What about everything else?
Did you guys see anything?
"Hickory dickory dock."
- Nothing but blood.
- It doesn't matter.
As long as we steer clear of
whichever sector is active, we'll be safe.
Yeah. Relatively speaking.
Change it up. Spin it.
Come on! Come on!
Hold on!
No!
Okay. That's enough.
Let's see how they tell time now.
You okay?
Let's just get what we need
and get off the bloody island.
So besides Brutus and Enobaria, who's left?
Maybe Chaff.
- Just those three.
- They know they're outnumbered.
I doubt they'll attack again.
We're safe here on the beach.
So what do we do? We hunt 'em down?
Katniss, help me!
Prim!
- Prim! Prim!
- No!
Katniss! Katniss, wait!
Prim! Prim!
Prim!
Katniss!
Help me! Help me!
- You okay?
- Finnick!
Finnick!
- No! It's not her.
- Annie!
Annie!
- Annie! Annie!
- Finnick! It's not her.
It's just a jabberjay. It's not her.
Well, how do you think they got that sound?
- Jabberjays copy.
- Katniss!
Gale.
Come on, come on, come on!
Peeta!
Stop, stop, stop! It's okay!
It's okay! They're
just mutts! It's not real!
It's over. It's okay. They're gone.
The hour's gone.
The hour's up. It's all right.
- Prim! Find Prim!
- No, no. Prim's okay.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Okay? They won't touch Prim. All right?
Your fiancé's right.
The whole country loves your sister.
If they tortured her
or did anything to her,
forget the districts,
there would be riots in the damn Capitol.
Hey, how does that sound, Snow?
What if we set your backyard on fire?
You know, you can't put everybody in here.
What?
They can't hurt me.
There's no one left that I love.
I'll get you some water.
Thank you.
Who's Annie?
Annie Cresta. The girl
Mags volunteered for.
She won, like, four
years... Five years ago.
Is she the one that went a little...
Love is weird.
I have a plan.
Finnick!
Where do the Careers feel safest?
The jungle?
The jungle's a nightmare.
Probably here on the beach.
Then why are they not here?
Because we are. We claimed it.
And if we left, they would come.
Or stay hidden in the tree line.
Which in just over four hours will be
soaked with water from the 10:00 wave.
And what happens at midnight?
- Lightning strikes that tree.
- Here's what I propose.
We leave the beach at dusk.
We head to the lightning tree.
That should draw them back to the beach.
Prior to midnight, we then run this wire
from the tree to the water.
Anyone in the water or on the damp sand
will be electrocuted.
How do we know
the wire's not gonna burn up?
Because I invented it.
I assure you, it won't burn up.
Well, it's better than hunting them down.
Yeah, why not?
If it fails, no harm done anyway, right?
All right, I say we try it.
So what can we do to help?
Keep me alive for the next six hours.
That would be extremely helpful.
I think we need to go.
This plan's gonna work.
I think so, too.
And once the Careers are dead,
we both know what happens next.
I don't want to be the
one that shoots first.
What if they don't either?
What if all of us refuse to shoot first?
We might still end up dead.
Maybe not.
I mean, it worked for us last time.
They're not gonna
make that same mistake again.
You know and I know there's
only one person walking out of here.
And it's gonna be one of us.
The Careers are still out there.
We should stick with these guys
till midnight.
And if we hear a cannon, we go.
Katniss, I don't know what kinda deals
you made with Haymitch
but he made me promises, too.
If you die and I live,
I'd have nothing.
Nobody else that I care about.
Peeta.
It's different for you.
Your family needs you.
You have to live.
For them.
What about you?
Nobody needs me.
I do.
I need you.
All right, lovebirds!
She is preparing to fight.
That's our girl.
This is what you predicted.
Moves and countermoves.
Indeed.
We'll toast when it's done?
In the meantime, make yourself comfortable.
Minimal charring.
It's an impressive conductor.
Let's get started.
Typically a lightning strike
contains five billion joules of energy.
We don't want to be anywhere
in the vicinity when this hits.
You two girls, go together now.
Take this. Unspool it carefully.
Make sure the entire coil is in the water.
You understand?
Then head to the tree at the 2:00 sector.
We'll meet you there.
I'm gonna go with them as a guard.
No, no, no.
You're staying here to protect me.
And the tree.
No, I need to go with her.
There are two Careers out there.
I need two guards.
Finnick can protect
you just fine on his own.
Why can't Finnick and Johanna stay
with you and Peeta and I'll take the coil?
You all agreed to keep me alive
till midnight, correct?
It's his plan. We all agreed to it.
Is there a problem here?
Excellent question.
No. There's no problem.
I'll see you at midnight.
All right, let's go!
Come on.
I want to put as much distance
between me and this beach as possible.
Frying is not how I want to go.
There's something...
Stay down.
Come on.
Johanna, where are you?
Johanna?
Peeta.
Beetee. Beetee!
Peeta!
Katniss, where are you?
Let it fly, Miss Everdeen.
Let it fly.
Katniss.
Remember who the real enemy is.
Katniss, get away from that tree!
It's not possible.
Heavensbee!
Plutarch Heavensbee!
Sir, we've lost power.
She's gonna lose it
when she finds out about the boy.
She'll still cooperate, though?
Without Peeta? There's no guarantee.
Just tell her her win...
Morning, sweetheart.
What are you doing with them?
You and a syringe against The Capitol?
See, this is why
no one lets you make the plans.
- What the hell are you doing in here?
- Stop.
Stop. Just listen.
We couldn't tell you with Snow watching.
It was too risky.
Better for you to know nothing.
Where's Peeta?
Now, Katniss...
You have been our mission
from the beginning.
The plan was always to get you out.
Half the Tributes were in on it.
This is the revolution.
And you are the Mockingjay.
And we're on our way
to District 13 right now.
13?
13. Yes.
Where's Peeta?
He still has his tracker in his arm.
Johanna cut yours out.
Where is he?
In The Capitol.
They got him and Johanna.
You son of a bitch! You son of a...
You promised me that
you would save him over me!
You promised me!
You're a liar. You're a liar.
Hey, Catnip.
You're okay.
You've just been asleep for a few days.
Are we home?
Gale?
Where's Prim?
She's alive.
So is your mother. I got 'em out in time.
Got them out?
After The Games, they sent in hovercrafts.
And they started dropping firebombs.
They're not in 12?
There is no District 12.
It's all gone.